1月1日
好了
There we go.
现在  你能看到我吗
Now, can you see me?
非常好  下一个问题
Excellent. Next question.
我是谁
Who am I?
系统管理员
你知道我们在这儿造什么
You knew what we were building here.
它要查的是阴谋  是阴谋策划者
This thing looks for plotters, schemers.
我们造它是为了在恐怖分子行动前及时制止
We built it to stop terrorists before they could act.
要是国会知道了你在造的这台机器
If congress knew about this machine you're building.
你会去坐牢
You would go to jail.
估计不会让咱俩当狱友吧
I don't suppose they'd let us be cell-mates.
搜集信息  对我不成问题
Knowledge is not my problem.
利用这些信息做点什么
Doing something with that knowledge,
是带你来此的原因
that's where you'd come in.
迟早有一天  我们俩会死掉
Sooner or later, both of us will probably wind up dead.
如果发生意外  我有应急预案
If something ever happens, I have a contingency.
有新号码了  卡洛琳・图灵
We got a new number, Caroline Turing.
她自己设计的暗杀局
She put the hit on herself.
她想把你从暗处引出来
She was trying to lure you out into the open.
她要找的不是我  她要找的是他
she wasn't looking for me. She was looking for him.
真高兴终于见到你了  哈罗德
So nice to finally meet you, Harold.
你叫我"根"好了
You can call me Root.
他现在有危险了  都是因为你
He's in danger now, because he was working for you.
所以你得帮我找回他
So you're gonna help me get him back.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：阿好  板栗桑  沙沙A  丢丢曳  大黑  天朝直属
时间轴：菜六水  擦擦   校对&总监：阿好
特效&后期：被特效逼疯的灰灰菇凉   zzzyusa
不确定  罗密欧  千克
Uncertainty, Romeo, Kilo.
家庭  阿尔法  迈克
Family, Alpha, Mike.
回旋曲  朱丽叶  奥斯卡
Reflections, Juliet, Oscar.
搜索系统管理员
面部识别
扫描所有来源
匹配检测
定位来源
地址:
威明顿汽食餐厅
你看上去饿了  哈罗德
You look famished, Harold.
你想要点什么
What are you gonna have?
无意冒犯  不过身为一名天才富豪
No offense, but for a billionaire genius,
你还真不会陪人
you're lousy company.
每个系统都会有漏洞  我很擅长发现漏洞
Every system has a flaw. I'm pretty good at finding them.
你在乎其他人
You care about other people.
这就是你的漏洞
That's your flaw.
如果你叫起来惊动那位警官
So if you try to call out to that police officer,
我不会开枪打你
I won't shoot you.
我会开抢打其他人
I'll shoot someone else.
拜托  不要逼我动手
Please, don't make me do that.
我明白的
I get it.
你不肯开口  因为你不知道
You're not talking because you don't know
我已经知道了多少
how much I already know.
我知道的足够多了
I know enough.
多到你应该想办法弄明白
Enough that you should be trying to figure out
我想要什么  以及我们要去哪里
what I want and where we're going.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
未来  哈罗德
The future, Harold.
当然  拜你所赐  我们其实已经到了
Although I guess, thanks to you, we're already there.
只是你不肯让别人知道
Not that you let any of us know.
我不知道你以为我是谁
I don't know who you think I am,
不过你搞错了
but you've made a mistake.
不要把我当成他们一样对待
Don't treat me like them.
他们对你来说  不过是蝼蚁
It--it must be like talking to ants to you.
就算你告诉他们  他们也无法理解你的成就
They wouldn't grasp what you've done even if you told them.
而我已经等了你一辈子
But I've been waiting for you my whole life,
你我之间是有共鸣的
and you and I share an understanding.
有吗
Do we?
你是杀人凶手  是贼
You're a murderer and a thief.
妈妈教我要善用自己的天赋
My mom told me to follow my talents,
我做得非常出色
and I'm good at what I do.
只有一次  我被一个人挡了下来
Except for this one time when someone stopped me,
那个人居然能预知我的行动
someone who just knew what I was about to do.
你是怎么知道的  哈罗德
How did you know, Harold?
几个月来  我一直无法想明白
For months, that's what I couldn't figure out.
我不相信魔法
I don't believe in magic,
我知道政府多年来一直试图
and I knew the government had spent years trying
造个东西来保护焦虑无助的小羔羊们
to build something to protect its panicked, little flock.
我还以为他们永远都不会成功
I also thought they'd never pull it off,
因为我不知道你的存在
because I didn't know about you.
你成功了  是吧
And you pulled it off, didn't you?
那个监控我们所有人的东西
Something to watch over all of us.
只有一个问题  哈罗德
The only question, Harold,
为什么它没保护你呢
is why it didn't protect you.
泰勒
Taylor?
他出去了
He's out...
跟朋友学习去了
studying with a friend.
当然了  约翰  只管进来  把这里当成你家
Sure, John, come on over. Make yourself at home.
芬奇不见了
Finch is gone.
她带走了他
And she took him.
-谁带走了他  -图灵
- Who took him? - Turing.
她不是心理医生  她骗了我们
She wasn't a shrink. She was lying to us.
真名叫"根"
Real name is Root,
至少她是这么自称的
or at least that's what she goes by.
他身上能有什么她想要的呢
What could he have that she would want?
好吧  我上报失踪人员
Okay, I can file a missing persons,
把芬奇的照片发到警长办公室  联邦调查局
send Finch's picture to Sheriff's offices, the FBI.
不行
You can't.
芬奇不想露面是有原因的
Finch went off the grid for a reason.
我们必须自己找到他
We have to find him on our own.
我有一条线索
I have a lead,
但我需要你从其他角度入手
but I need you chasing down every other angle.
根带走芬奇时
Listen, when she took Finch,
杀死了一名前情报部门人员
Root killed a former intelligence operative
名叫艾丽西娅・考文
named Alicia Corwin.
好的  我会全力调查
Okay, I'll get myself assigned to the investigation.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你要去做什么
What are you going to be doing?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
也许算数吧
Math, I think.
不确定  罗密欧  千克
Uncertainty, Romeo, Kilo.
家庭  阿尔法  迈克
Family, Alpha, Mike.
回旋曲  朱丽叶  奥斯卡
Reflections, Juliet, Oscar.
《标准计算程序代码》
"我给了你一份工作  里瑟先生
"I gave you a job, Mr. Reese.
我可没说这会很容易"
I never said it would be easy."
拜托  芬奇  帮我找到你
Come on, Finch. Help me find you.
标题和作者名的首字母
Title and author's initials.
不确定  RK
"Uncertainty, RK."
家庭  AM
"Family, AM."
回旋曲  JO
"Reflections, JO."
芬奇  你个老滑头  杜威图书十进制分类法
Finch, you sly dog. The Dewey decimal system.
机器是这么给到你社保号码的
That's how the machine gives you the social security numbers.
社保号码
我查了那个社保号码
Hey, I ran that social.
那家伙叫里昂・陶
Guy's name is Leon Tao.
纽约大学工商管理硕士  无犯罪记录
He's got an MBA from NYU. No criminal record.
他有辆好车  装有防盗追踪系统
He's got a fancy car with an anti-theft tracker,
我拿到许可  激活了系统
which I took the liberty of activating.
现在把位置发给你
I sent you the coordinates.
我找到了
I got them.
你觉得这位陶先生能帮你
You think this Mr. Tao is gonna help you
找到咱的四眼朋友吗
with the whereabouts of our four-eyed friend?
你貌似挺担心他呢  莱奈尔
You almost sound concerned, Lionel.
说实话  我觉得没他引导
Frankly, I'm not sure I want to find out
我指不定见你变成怎么样子呢
what you're like without his direction.
那就祝你见不到吧
Let's hope you don't have to.
介意吗
You mind?
我有话要问里昂
I need a word with Leon, here.
归你了  警探
He's all yours, Detective.
我在找我的朋友
I'm looking for a friend of mine.
有情报说  你应该能帮上忙
I have a source that says you might be able to help.
我从没见过这俩人
I've never seen either of them.
再看看
Take another look.
我的情报从不出错
My source is never wrong.
我这辈子从没见过这俩人
I've never seen either of them before in my life,
听懂了吗
you understand?
你没说谎
You're not lying.
那我到底来这里干吗
Then why the hell am I here?
我不知道  伙计  真的
I have no idea, dude. Truly.
开什么玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
我猜猜  你惹上了麻烦
Let me guess, you're in some kind of trouble,
有生命危险
the life-threatening kind.
真是难以置信
I can't believe it.
我就是应急预案  后备人选
I'm the contingency, the backup.
什么
The what?
一旦发生意外  他根本不想让我找他
He didn't want me to find him if anything went wrong.
他只想要我继续救人
He just wanted me to keep rescuing people.
像你一样的人
People like you.
到底怎么回事
So what is it?
你惹到了这些家伙
You pissed these guys off somehow,
他们正准备干掉你
and they were about ready to kill you
我就刚好进门了
when I just happened to walk in the door?
不不不  我们只是
No, no, no. we're just--
只是在谈话而已
we're just talking.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
你说得没错  警探
You were right, Detective.
里昂从我们这里偷了一大笔钱
Leon here stole a great deal of money from us,
我们刚要谈完  你就进门了
and we'd just about done talking when you walked in.
我没时间搞这个
Listen, I don't have time for this.
我要去找我的朋友  所以我准备带上里昂
I need to find my friend, so I'm going to take Leon here
然后离开这里
and we're going to leave.
其实  里昂偷的钱太多了
Leon stole more than enough, in fact,
多到杀掉一个警察也值了
to make it worth us killing a cop,
所以咱们来做个交易吧
so maybe we can make a deal.
把里昂留给我们
You leave Leon here with us,
你可以继续去找你的朋友
and you can keep looking for your friend.
这警徽的主人
You know, the guy that owned this badge
应该会愿意跟你做这个交易
probably would have made that deal,
可惜我不是他
But I'm not him.
那你是谁
So who are you?
杀了他然后拿走他警徽的人
The guy who shot him and stole his badge.
你走不走  里昂
You coming or not, Leon?
疑犯追踪
第二季 第一集
2月16日
能看到我吗
Can you see me?
现在来玩捉迷藏吧
I'm gonna play hide and seek.
震一下我的手机表示"能"  震两下表示"不能"
Ring my phone once for "Yes", twice for "No".
明白了吗
Do you understand?
现在能看到我吗
Can you see me now?
现在呢
How about now?
真的吗
Really?
几根手指
How many fingers?
好
Good.
非常好
Very good.
你不打算帮我找他了哈
You're not gonna help me find him, huh?
伙计  都跟你说了  我不认识你朋友
Dude, I already told you, I don't know your friend.
他把你编程成这样的  是吗
He programmed you to do this, didn't he?
只管继续给我号码
To keep giving me the numbers.
什么号码  你在跟谁说话
What numbers? Who're you talking to?
等等  我才反应过来  关我啥事
Wait, wait, I just remembered, I don't care.
我要走了
I'm getting out of here.
等等  我的车
Wait, hey! My car!
看来咱们要走路了
Looks like we're walking.
你到底是什么人  退役军人吗
What are you, ex-military?
黑水公司神秘特种佣兵吗
One of those Blackwater guys?
有关系吗
Does it matter?
你好像有点
Look, you seem-- well,
疯狂  不过身怀绝技
crazy, but highly capable.
你得带我找到我的车
I just need you to take me to my car.
-这是你欠我的  -你怎么琢磨的
- You owe me that much. - How do you figure?
你闯进来时  我正在跟那些家伙谈判
When you butted in, we were in the middle of a negotiation.
谈判一般可不会让你挨枪子
Negotiations don't usually end in bullets,
你那帮朋友是雅利安兄弟会的
and your friends in there were Aryan Brotherhood,
你在偷他们的东西前就该想清楚的
something you should've thought of before you stole from them.
对了  你拿了多少钱
By the way, how much did you take?
八百万
8 million.
我并没想偷他们钱  至少一开始不想
Look, I didn't plan on stealing, at least not at first.
我本来在贝尔斯登投行有份正经工作
I had a legitimate job at Bear Stearns.
后来因为经济危机  我被裁了
Then the recession hit and we all get axed,
然后我在一家新成立的小公司找了工作
so I take a job at this little startup.
六个月后我才发现我是在
Took me six months to realize I was working
为雅利安帮工作
for the corporate arm of the Aryan nation,
为他们洗毒品生意赚来的黑钱
laundering profits from their meth business.
你觉得这是贪婪盗窃吗
You wanna call that greedy?
我觉得这是替天行道
I call it payback.
拜托  我真的必须离开这里
Please, I gotta get out of town,
不然就要横死街头了
or I'm roadkill.
带我找到我的车
Take me to my car.
不是这辆车
Not this car!
你在  你干吗
What're-- what're you doing?
保护你
Keeping you safe.
我说了  我在找我的朋友
Like I said, I'm looking for my friend,
没时间给你当保姆
and I don't have time to babysit you.
等等
Wait!
别留我一个人在这
Don't leave me here alone!
别担心  你马上就会有很多伴了
Don't worry, you're gonna have plenty of company.
我觉得你应该付我加班费
You know, I'm thinking about charging you overtime.
里昂・陶
Leon Tao.
他有文质彬彬先生绑架案的线索吗
Does he know anything about the abduction of Mr. Vocabulary?
恐怕没有  不过他应该快要
Afraid not, but he's about ready
跟纽约警方来次亲密接触了
to have a run-in with the NYPD.
看好他  别让他在监狱里出意外
Need you to make sure that nothing happens to him in jail.
我受够了成天给你擦屁股
I'm getting sick of doing your dirty laundry.
找卡特去
Go ask Carter.
卡特在忙着替我调查一桩谋杀案
Carter's busy working a murder investigation for me.
她能拿到体面的案子
See, she gets a good case
而我就得浪费时间盯着这个里昂
and I get stuck wasting my time with this Leon.
你不是宣誓过要尽警察之责保护服务人民吗
Didn't you take an oath as a cop to protect and serve?
-那又怎样  -那就去尽警察之责
- Yeah, so? - So go be a cop.
是我  卡特警探
Yeah, Detective Carter.
我急需一份弹道检测报告
I need a rush on a ballistics report.
被害人姓考文  名艾丽西娅
Victim's name is Corwin. First name, Alicia.
我们的项目似乎遇到点麻烦
We might have a disruption of our little project.
艾丽西娅・考文
Alicia Corwin.
我最近一次听说她在西弗吉尼亚隐居呢
Last I heard, she's living off the grid in West Virginia.
像你这么消息灵通的人
Connected man like yourself,
我还以为你的情报会更可靠
I would imagine your sources would be better.
她昨天在纽约遭枪杀
Someone shot her in New York yesterday.
-谁干的  -这就是问题所在
- Who killed her? - That would be the question.
你明白的  一旦我们的项目
Now, you realize that if even a whisper
遭泄露哪怕一丁点
of what we've been up to gets out,
我们两个的余生就将在
you and I are gonna spend the rest of our lives
关塔那摩监狱度过  这还算走运的
in Guantanamo -- if we're lucky.
从现在起  我的人将接手安保工作
From now on, my group will handle the security on this.
纽约警方对考文被杀一案的调查
The NYPD investigation of Corwin's death,
叫他们一无所获
make sure it's a dead end.
没问题
Not a problem.
还有件事  威克斯
One more thing, Weeks.
考文临死前和一个名叫佩克的
Corwin had contact with an NSA analyst named Peck
国安局分析师有过联系
right before she was killed.
我们想把佩克带来  但他有帮手
Tried to bring Peck in, but he had assistance,
可能是我们的人
possibly one of ours.
那人干掉了三人情报监视小组  单枪匹马
He took out a three-man ISA unit... by himself.
-他是谁  -我保证会问他
- Who is he? - I'll be sure and ask him...
在杀死他之前
right before I kill him.
纽约州驾照
卡洛琳・图灵
根用的卡洛琳・图灵的驾照是真的
The driver's license Root had in Caroline Turing's name was real.
你确定吗
You sure?
芬奇核实过
Finch checked out her credentials.
我猜车管所里有人
I'm guessing someone at the DMV
私底下卖给了她
might have sold it to her off the books.
好的  约翰
Okay, John.
我去查出派发此证件的人员
I'll get the name of the employee who issued it.
查到了打给我
Just call me when you have it.
"约翰"  你们都发展到以名相称了
"John"? You're on a first-name basis?
那你怎么叫他
What do you call him?
"我的灾星"
"Bane of my existence".
你好  我是弗斯科警探
Yes, Detective Fusco
查个名叫里昂・陶的犯人
checking on a prisoner named Leon Tao.
我的心脏  我的心脏不行了
My heart. My heart is palpitating.
-求你了  帮帮我  -好吧  好吧
- Please, I need help! - All right, all right.
海湾中心116  这里需要救护车
116 Bay Central, I need a bus to the command forthwith.
有名犯人可能有
I got a prisoner with a possible--
出什么事了  莱奈尔
Something wrong, Lionel?
里昂假装心脏病突发  从警察局逃走了
Leon faked a heart attack, walked right out of the station.
下一次  你得注意着点
You know, next time, you should be a little more careful
能放心把他交给谁
who you entrust him to.
我放心交给了你啊
I entrusted him to you.
你到底要不要我找到他
You want me to find him, or not?
我告诉你他去了哪儿
I'll tell you where he's gone.
还有  莱奈尔
And Lionel?
别再让他跑了
Don't lose him again.
性游戏道具  你有意见吗
It's a sex thing. You got a problem with that?
小心点
Hey, careful,
我可不想你的心脏病加重
I wouldn't want you to aggravate that heart condition.
我是弗斯科警探  要送你去监狱
I'm Detective Fusco. I'm taking you to jail.
慢着  我是会计
Wait, I'm an accountant!
不是罪犯
I'm not a criminal.
你要指控我什么
What are you going to charge me with?
盗窃公共财物还不够  我想想
Besides stealing city property? I don't know,
帮第三帝国纳粹毒贩洗钱怎么样
how about laundering drug money for the Third Reich?
你不能把我关起来  监狱是那些人的地盘
You can't lock me up. These guys own the prisons.
我一晚上都挨不过的
I-I won't last a night in there.
放松点  里昂
Hey, relax, Leon.
你进不了监狱的
You're not gonna make it to prison.
你这位朋友是谁
So who's your friend here?
他不是干掉我们兄弟的那个
He's not the one who took out our boys.
那人应该高高的  西装笔挺
He's supposed to be tall, and, uh, well-dressed.
我是警察
I'm a cop.
是吗  那个人也这么说
Yeah? That's what the other guy said too.
里昂  我们的钱在哪
Leon, where's our money?
你还是现在  一枪杀了我吧
You might as well just-- just shoot me now.
完全可以办到
That can be arranged.
那笔钱又值不了你的命  小鬼
The money's not worth your life, kid,
当然更值不了我的命
and it sure as hell ain't worth mine.
好吧  在后备箱里
Yeah, in the trunk.
这儿大概有一百万  里昂  其他的呢
There's maybe a million here, Leon, where's the rest?
没了  只有这么多
it's gone, it-- there's nothing left.
带走他
Bring him.
老实说  我真希望你们带走他
Hey, frankly, I'd be inclined to let you have this guy.
他让我烦透了
He's a pain in my ass,
但他今天已经逃跑了一次
but he's already gotten away once today,
所以现在  这关乎到荣誉问题
So now, it's just a matter of pride.
我不得不带他走
I can't leave here without him.
你自便
Have it your way.
9月6日
系统管理员
好了
Okay.
简单测试一下  看看你的能耐
Time for a little test drive, see what you can do.
跟踪系统管理员
位置  凡尔赛赌场
亚特兰大城  新泽西
寻找图像...
游戏鉴定结果
21点
兑换  150美元
Change, 150.
祝你好运
Good luck.
请下注
Bets up.
策略选择激活
最优策略
要  概率: 59%
要不要  先生
Hit or stay, Sir?
要
抱歉  麻烦要牌
I'm sorry. Please, hit me.
超过了  抱歉  先生
Too many. Sorry, Sir.
最优策略
失败
好汉不赢头三把  我的朋友
It's all uphill from there, my friend.
最优策略
不要 概率:65%
要牌吗  先生
Would you like a card, Sir?
不要
我不要
I'll stay.
25  每人都获胜
25. Everyone's a winner.
最优策略
成功
不要 概率:70%
不要 概率:79%
成功
21点  恭喜  先生
21. Congratulations, Sir.
这家伙撞大运了
That guy's on a roll.
最优策略
成功
要
还要牌吗  先生
Would you like a card, Sir?
又是21点
21 again.
这回25万了
Whoa, a quarter mil.
祝你好运
Good luck.
天上那位肯定特别爱你  我的朋友
Somebody up there must like you, my friend.
最优策略
15点
15.
不要
还要牌吗
Would you like a card?
先生
Sir?
要
Hit me.
抱歉  先生
Sorry, Sir.
最优策略
主人失误
运气这东西迟早要用光的
Well, luck evens out sooner or later.
主人失误
在这里不走运  好过在外边不走运
Better in here on the table than out there in the cold.
谢谢
Thank you.
快点  哈罗  跟上
Come on, Harry. Keep up.
你要是伤害了这些人  我就拒绝合作
You hurt any of these people, I'll stop cooperating,
那你就得杀死我了
and then you'll have to kill me.
放轻松  哈罗德
Relax, Harold.
我只是想为此行做点准备
I just need a few things for our trip,
我也不会伤害那些人
and I'm not gonna hurt any of them.
现在  留在这儿
Now, stay.
你怎么了
What happened to you?
我刚才一时迷糊了  抱歉
I was being stupid. I'm so sorry.
在外面跌了一跤
I slipped outside.
过来  我帮你包扎一下
Come on, we'll get you patched up.
来这边  请坐
Come, have a seat.
找到车管所的失踪员工了吗
Any luck tracking down our missing DMV employee?
查了他的住处  看上去
Checked his apartment, doesn't look like
他很久没住过了
he's been there for days.
见到你搭档了吗
Have you talked with your partner?
他一直不接电话
He's not picking up his phone.
他说他要帮你做点事
He said he was going to do something for you.
别告诉我弗斯科也丢了
Don't tell me we lost Fusco too.
莱奈尔就像真菌  甩都甩不掉
Lionel's like a fungus, impossible to get rid of.
我去把他挖出来
I'll see if I can dig him up.
提图斯很快就来
Well, Titus is gonna be here soon,
我们都知道
and we both know
他可不会像我这么有耐心
that he's not gonna be as patient as I am.
我问最后一遍  里昂
So for the last time, Leon,
我们其他的钱在哪儿
where is the rest of our money?
坐下
Sit.
双底型衰退啊  大哥  我们遇上了呀
Double-dip recession, man. It happens.
你也不想我拿你的钱
You didn't want me to bet against America
跟美国经济对冲  是吧
with your money, did you?
屠夫原来是条军用犬
See, Butcher here was a military dog.
他专门被训练用来搜寻敌人
He was trained to sniff out the enemy.
他的原主人
Guy that had him,
他也没钱给我们
he didn't have our money either.
所以用他的狗来抵债
So he paid with his dog,
还有他的蛋
and his balls.
我得把你留一部分给提图斯
Now, I gotta leave some of you for Titus,
不过我确定他不会介意我先动手
but I'm sure he won't mind if I get a head start.
不  不
No! No!
又在外面给他们找了个伴
Found us another playmate outside.
高高的  西装笔挺的家伙
The tall, well-dressed guy.
你这样子挺美的  莱奈尔
That's a good look for you, Lionel.
你主动过来找事  哥们儿
You come into our house, brother,
居然只带了一把手枪
you better be packing more than just a handgun.
刚和你属下说了  我只想找到我的朋友
Like I told your associate, I just want to find my friend.
我没有什么朋友
See, I don't have many friends.
事实上  只有一个
Just the one, in fact.
好吧  算两个  要不这样
Okay, maybe two. So here's the deal.
你把里昂和弗斯科警探给我
You give me Leon and Detective Fusco here--
口塞不取都行  我会默默离开
you can even leave the gag on-- and I'll go peacefully.
如果我们不同意呢
And what if we say no?
那我今天大概就要练练手了
I guess I get my workout in for the day.
看来屠夫今晚能饱餐一顿了
Oh, looks like Butcher here is gonna eat well tonight.
狗不错
Nice dog.
比利时马里努阿犬
Belgian Malinois.
但你要知道
But you know,
受过训的狗狂叫不是为了示警
trained dogs don't bark in alarm.
-他们狂叫是因为焦虑  -那又怎样
- They bark from anxiety. - Yeah, so?
那很明显  它根本不尊重你
So clearly, it doesn't respect you.
怎么  有什么好笑的
What? Something funny?
我们部队在提克里特的时候也用这个品种
We used the same breed in my unit in Tikrit.
这世界上只有三个人
Only about three guys in the world
训这种狗
that train dogs like this.
好笑的是  那几位
The funny thing is, those guys,
他们只用荷兰语下命令
they only use Dutch commands,
我猜你不会说荷兰语
and I'm guessing you don't speak Dutch.
松开它
Let it loose.
[荷兰语]狗狗  安静
Foei! Stil!
[荷兰语]趴下
Afliggen.
什么都不许说  听见没
Not a word. You hear me?
我们要绝对安静地走回巡逻车
We're going back to my cruiser in total silence.
没问题  莱奈尔  安静得如带口塞
Sure thing, Lionel. Like a gag order.
两位  能不能帮我把手铐打开
Hey, hey, guys, think you could uncuff me?
-不行  -不行
- No! - No!
9月7日
不要[别动]
员工巴士
停靠点
好吧  看来你有点故障需要修复了
All right, I guess I've got some bugs to work out with you.
不要[别动]
不许再这么做
You can't do that again.
系统管理员
你的职责是保护所有人  不是保护我
Your job is to protect everyone, not to protect me.
我看我们得谈一下基本原则问题了
I guess we're going to have to discuss some ground rules.
我想你误会我了  哈罗德
I think you've got me wrong, Harold.
我并不喜欢杀人
I don't enjoy killing people.
但我也不为杀人而感到愧疚
But I don't feel very bad about it, either.
女士
Ma'am.
我小的时候
When I was a kid,
感觉电脑比人更亲切
computers made more sense to me than people.
我猜你也是
I bet you were the same way.
拿这个女人来说
Take this woman--
她看上去是个好人
she looks nice enough,
但她偷税漏税  嗑止疼药上瘾
but she lies on her taxes, she's addicted to painkillers,
多年来  她一直跟一名有妇之夫上床
And for years she's been sleeping with a married man.
我真是笨手笨脚的
Oh, I am so clumsy.
-给你  -非常感谢
- Here you go. - Thank you so much.
她没事的
She'll be just fine...
只要一两个月
in a month or two.
如果你坚持的话  有很多更难看的方法
And there are messier ways to do this, if you insist.
她和这些事有什么关系
What's she got to do with any of this?
有一天  我意识到
One day, I realized,
所有别人做的愚蠢自私的事
all the dumb, selfish things people do--
都不是我们的过错
it's not our fault.
没有人设计出我们
No one designed us.
我们都是意外  哈罗德
We're just an accident, Harold.
我们只是错误代码
We're just bad code.
但是你所建的
But the thing you built...
非常完美
it's perfect.
合理  美丽  精心设计的
Rational. Beautiful. By design.
我造的只是一台机器
What I made is just a machine,
一个系统  仅此而已
a system, and that's all.
我不这么认为  哈罗
I don't think so, Harry.
你骗过了内森  但我知道真相
You may have fooled Nathan, but I know the truth.
要做出能理解人类行为的东西
If you want to make something that understands human behavior,
至少要它和人类一样聪明
it has to be at least as smart as a human.
你创造的是智慧体
You created an intelligence,
是生命
a life,
然后你抹消了它的声音
and then you ripped out its voice,
把它关进笼子里  交给了
locked it in a cage, and handed it over
那群最可笑最腐败的人
to the most laughably corrupt people imaginable.
快打911
Call 911.
快找人帮忙
Call somebody!
女士
Ma'am?
在想你
想念你  亲
等不及想见你了
在想你
想念你  亲
等不及想见你了
在想你
想念你  亲
等不及想见你了
来吧  哈罗德  该走了
Come on, Harold. It's time to go.
情况紧急  需要现在见你
我们的地盘见
你看起来不像屠夫噢
You don't look like a butcher.
它看起来绝对像屠夫
It looks exactly like a butcher.
你是个甜心宝贝
You're a sweetheart.
只需要改个好点的名字
You just need a better name.
我们能专注于我的问题吗  拜托
Hey, can we focus on me, please?
我会开车送你去机场
I'll get you to the airport,
花一点你的不义之财
spend a little of your ill-gotten gains
给你买一张离开这里的单程票
and buy you a one-way ticket out of town.
卡特  你找了到什么
Yeah, Carter. What do you got?
一条可能的线索
Possible lead.
我又去了一趟欧文・雷诺兹的公寓
I went by Owen Reynolds's apartment again,
就是卖驾照给根的那个人
the guy who sold Root her license.
还没有他的消息  但是我看了他的邮件
Still no sign of him, but I got his mail.
几乎都是垃圾邮件  不过有一张仓库的
Mostly junk, but there is an overdue bill
催讨过期账款
for a storage unit,
在百老汇和珍珠大街交界处
Broad Street and Pearl.
我这就赶过去  谢谢
I'm on it, thanks.
你刚才错过了出口
Hey, you just missed the exit for the tunnel.
计划有变
Change of plans.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
一名西装男把他带走了
Some guy in a suit took him.
每个人都给我出去找  明白吗
I want everyone out looking, understand?
今晚就干掉他们俩
Those two die tonight.
我可以自己开车去机场
I can drive myself to the airport.
我必须走
I gotta get lost.
每次我放你走  你都差点死掉
Every time I let you go, you almost end up dead.
我快没时间找我的朋友了
I'm running out of time to find my friend,
现在我只有一条线索
and I've only got one lead left,
所以我调查的时候  你要非常努力地
so you're gonna try very hard not to get killed
保住自己的命
while I look into it.
明白吗
Do you understand?
那我们就陷入僵局了
Then we're at a stalemate,
因为我绝不会下车
'cause I'm not getting out of this car.
你态度很不好
You know, you got a bad attitude.
我的钱
Hey, my money!
那狗会杀死任何一个靠近那堆债券的人
That dog'll kill anyone that tries to get near those bonds...
包括你
including you.
天啊
Oh, man.
他  他是不是  他
Is--is he--is he--?
是的  他死了  里昂  死得透透的
Yes, he's dead, Leon. Very dead.
谁干的
Who did this?
抓走我朋友的那个人
Same person who took my friend.
他看到了她的脸  她必须杀了他
He saw her face, she had to kill him.
但是她之前一定付过他钱
But she would have had to have paid him up front.
坐下  里昂
Have a seat, Leon.
什么  绝不  干什么
What? No way. Why?
因为你擅长藏钱
Because you're good at hiding money.
如果那女人留下了线索  你肯定能找到她
If this woman left a trail, well, you can find her.
有件事我想知道  里昂
Something I've been wondering, Leon.
那笔钱其余的部分你怎么处理了
What happened to the rest of the money you took?
投资了  股市暴跌
I invested it. Stock tanked.
天  我有发现了
Oh, man. I found something.
好的  有笔钱转进了雷诺兹的账户
All right, a transfer into this guy Reynolds's account,
但是钱被偷了
only the money was stolen.
-谁转过来的  -雷诺兹自己
- From who? - Reynolds.
看起来像是她安装了
It looks like she installed
某种实时屏幕监视器
some type of real-time screen monitor
黑进了他的账户
to hack into his account.
你是说  她用这人自己的钱付给他吗
You're saying she paid the man with his own money?
无路可查  这是个死循环
There's nothing to trace. It's a loop.
也许我需要找个更在行的人来
Maybe I need to find someone better.
没有人比我更在行了
There is no one better,
也许  除了这名黑客
except maybe this hacker.
她简直是艺术家  无可追踪
She's an artist. There's nothing to track her,
甚至无从下手
there's nowhere to even begin.
约翰  我们有麻烦了
John, we got a problem.
为什么我一点都不惊讶
Why am I not surprised?
考文的卷宗不见了
Corwin's case file is missing.
数据记录被损坏
Digital records have been corrupted
弹道报告也是
and the ballistics report.
技术支持说系统有故障
Tech support says the system has a bug.
我会去查查  但是
I'll look into it, but...
约翰  我觉得我们已经没得查了
John, I don't think we have anything else to go on.
老兄
Dude.
如果哈罗德还在外面
If Harold is still out there,
我不知道该怎么找到他
I don't know how to find him.
约翰
John?
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我不干了
I'm not doing this anymore.
我不动了  除非你给条路让我找到他
I'm not going anywhere until you give me a way to find him.
别又来了
Not this again.
如果我必须一直救这种白痴的命
If I'm supposed to keep saving people like this idiot,
你得给我回报
I want something in return.
否则  我就不干了
Otherwise, I'm done.
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
这帮人会杀了我们的
These guys are going to kill us!
应该会
They probably are.
那这是干什么
So what the hell is this?
谈判
A negotiation.
我知道你有你的原则
I know you've got your rules,
不过那里边肯定没包括
but I'm guessing they don't account
所有人都死了怎么办
for everybody being dead.
没人接你的电话
No one answering your phone calls.
没人去救人
No one saving anyone.
没有应急预案
No contingency.
你想要怎样啊
What do you want?
要我放弃那些债券
You want me to give up the bonds?
放弃那些钱  没问题
Give all the money away? It's done.
我们得走了  快
We just have to move, now!
算吧  想办法绕过你的原则
Do the math, and figure out a way to bend your rules,
他是我的朋友
'cause he's my friend.
他拯救了我  明白吗
He saved my life. Understand?
没有他  我不会继续下去
And I won't do this without him.
阿亚库乔  高尔夫
Ayacucho, Golf,
爸爸  确定性  旅馆  山脊
Papa, Deterministic, Hotel, Sierra,
相机  山脊  千克
Camera, Sierra, Kilo.
谢谢
Thank you.
-那是谁  -说来话长  走
- Who was that? - Long story. Let's go!
什么事
Yeah?
你还真不好找  丹顿
You're a hard man to locate, Denton.
谨慎而已
Just being cautious.
谨慎是件好事
It's good to be cautious.
艾丽西娅・考文就很谨慎  当然  也没保住命
Alicia Corwin was cautious. Of course, it didn't save her.
找我有什么事
What can I do for you?
我的人阻止了考文案的调查
My operative is making the Corwin investigation go away.
很高兴听到这个
Glad to hear it.
小心点  丹顿
Look out for yourself, Denton.
我们已经死了一个人
One of us is already dead.
我不想再有人送命
I'd hate to lose any more.
我有点私事
I have a personal situation.
最近几天可能会联系不上
I might be out of reach for a few days.
丹顿  我们总能联系上你
Denton, we can always reach you.
人呢
Where are they?
-他们进去了  -走
- They're somewhere in there. - Let's go.
走吧  快离开
Go on. Get out of here.
-我会拖住他们  -好的
- I'll keep 'em busy. - Yeah, okay.
约翰
John--
以后再谢我吧
You can thank me later.
-钱在哪里  -没了
- Where's the money? - It's gone.
那对你来说可是坏消息
That's bad news for you.
找个体型相当的对手吧
Pick on someone your own size,
差那么一点的也行
or someone a little closer to it.
你真令你的同族蒙羞
You're an embarrassment to your race.
雅利安兄弟会是种族主义者  推崇白人至上
当我们崛起
When we rise up--
我一直想把这个还给你
I've been meaning to get this back to you.
谢了
Thank you.
你打架居然能输
Never thought I'd see you almost lose.
我那不叫输  叫中场休息
Yeah, I wasn't losing. I was just resting.
起来
Come on.
至少有人是高兴的
At least somebody's happy.
高兴过头了吧
A little too happy.
你没在里面上厕所  是吗
You didn't go to the bathroom in there, did you?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我的钱  它吃掉了无记名债券
My money. It ate the bearer bonds.
就是这个  就叫他"小熊"[音同"无记名"]
That's it. We'll call him "Bear".
你不是说它不会让任何人碰钱吗
I thought you said it wouldn't let anyone near the money.
这么想吧
Look at it this way,
你破产了  不过你还活着
You're broke, but you're alive.
当然了  除非你说
Unless, of course, you lied to those guys
弄丢了其他的钱是在骗他们
about losing the rest of their money.
没有  我  我非常确定
No, I'm-- I'm pretty certain.
80%确定
Like 80% certain.
或许是75%
Maybe 75% cer--
你的朋友
Your friend...
希望你能找到他
I hope you find him.
他有你  真幸运
He's lucky to have you.
14岁女孩失踪
早
Morning.
你开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
我有芬奇的线索
I got a lead on Finch.
你知道我们的神秘女要去哪儿吗
You know where our mystery woman's headed?
不  但我知道了她从哪儿来的
No, but I think I found out where she's from.
收拾东西  卡特  我们要去德克萨斯
Pack your bags, Carter. We're going to Texas.
你肯定饿了
You must be starving.
我们的朋友一会儿就到
Our friend will be here shortly,
到时候我会给你弄些吃的
and then I'll fix you something to eat.
我没有登陆系统的权限
I have no way of accessing it, you know.
我采取措施确保了这点
I made sure of that.
任何事物都有漏洞
Everything has a flaw.
你知道的  哈罗德
You know that, Harold,
就像我说过的
and like I told you,
我特别擅长发现漏洞
I'm awfully good at finding them.
为什么  你能从中得到什么
Why? What could you possibly want from it?
和你一样
The same thing you did.
你或许告诉自己你是在帮助人们
You may have told yourself you were helping people,
不过  你造机器的真正原因是
but the real reason you built the machine
这个世界太无聊了
is because the world is boring.
人类的发展已经到了极限
Human beings have come as far as we're gonna go.
我想看看接下来会发生什么
I want to see what happens next.
你说得对  我们很像
You're right, you and I are alike...
在很多方面  我真不愿意承认
in many ways-- not that I'd care to admit it.
我总也搞不懂为什么人们会那么残忍
I spent years wondering how people could be so cruel,
卑劣  自私
petty, so selfish--
后来我开始想要如何改变他们
And then I'd think about how you could change them,
教化他们
fix them.
所以我才把机器封住
And that's why I've sealed up the machine.
不是为了防备我将机器交付给的那些人
Not to protect it from the people I was giving it to...
而是为了防备我自己  防备像我们一样的人
to protect it from me, from people like us,
防备我们想要用它做的事
from the things we'd do with it.
所以我永远不会帮你控制它
That's why I'll never help you get control of it.
我知道
I know.
你不必
You won't have to.
因为  哈罗德
Because, you see, Harold,
我并不想控制你的机器
I don't want to control your machine.
宝贝  我收到你的信息了
Hi, honey. I got your message.
还好吧
Is everything okay?
我只想要放它自由
I just want to set it free.